Thorvald F. Hammer Papers
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Thorvald F. Hammer Papers.
undated, 1854-1987.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Hammer, Thorvald F.
27.5 linear feet.
Thorvald Hammer was born in 1893. He was a leading industrialist and engineer in the state of Connecticut for over fifty years. He graduated from Yale University in 1918 and went on to serve in the U.S. Navy during the First World War. Thorvald Hammer became the president of the Malleable Iron Fittings Company (MIF) in 1935. An accomplished engineer, Mr. Hammer contributed to the development of the galvanizing process and was the holder of several original patents. After resigning from the presidency, Mr. Hammer assumed the position of Chairman of the Board. He died in 1987 at the age of 93.
MSS19890096
Biography
Thorvald Frederick Hammer (1893-1987) was a leading industrialist and engineer in the state of Connecticut for over fifty years. He became president of the Malleable Iron Fittings Company (MIF) in 1935 upon the death of the former president, his father, Alfred E. Hammer. His family had been involved in the management of MIF from its inception in 1864. He had started working with the company at the age of fourteen during his summer vacations and became a permanent employee after graduating from Yale University in 1918 and serving in the U.S. Navy during the First World War. He remained in active service with the company until 1969.
As president of the company, he embarked on a program of modernization, which put the production of malleable iron castings on an assembly line basis. At the same time, he installed dust elimination systems and shower bath facilities to protect the health and safety of employees and to improve the environment of the work place.
Mr. Hammer was also an accomplished engineer in his own right. He made a significant contribution to the development of the galvanizing process and was the holder of several original patents. In 1962, Mr. Hammer resigned the presidency and assumed the position of Chairman of the Board when the company was sold to a group of Connecticut businessmen headed by Robert E. Thompson. Thompson became President of the company. In 1969, the company was sold to Waltham Industries and Mr. Hammer retired chairman emeritus. During his retirement, he was an independent engineering consultant.
Thorvald F. Hammer was also a prominent member of several business boards including Southern Connecticut Gas Co., the American Mutual Insurance Co., and the regional board of the Connecticut National Bank. He was a founder of the Branford Historical Society and served as chairman of the Blackstone Memorial Library of Branford, Connecticut, from 1951 to 1986.
He was a lifelong resident of Branford, Connecticut. He was the husband of State Senator Lucy T. Hammer, and they had one daughter, Alexandra Hammer Clark. He died in 1987 at the age of 93.
(Additional biographical information about Mr. Hammer may be found in Series VI, Memorabilia, Biographical and Historical Records.)
Scope and Content
The papers of Thorvald F. Hammer chronicle the life and career of one of Connecticut's most prominent and gifted industrialists of the twentieth century. They also describe in part the day-to-day workings of the Malleable Iron Fittings (MIF) Company, which Mr. Hammer was involved in the management of for over fifty years. In addition, it provides a close-up view of the Connecticut iron industry, which once formed an integral part of the state's economy.
The papers span the period from 1890 to 1987. They contain Thorvald F. Hammer's personal and business correspondence, a variety of company records such as reports and surveys, personnel records, production and reference materials, historical data about the Malleable Iron Fittings Company, and biographical information concerning Mr. Hammer. The papers contain very little about the Hammer family itself except for a small amount of personal correspondence between Mr. Hammer and his family and friends.
Arrangement
Series I: Corresepondence ( undated, 1931-1981 ) contains correspondence to and from Thorvald F. Hammer. The correspondence is divided into three categories: Personal and Individual Business, Companies and Corporate, and Interoffice Memoranda. The first category contains correspondence of a personal or business nature addressed to or from individuals and is filed in alphabetical order by correspondent's name. The bulk of Mr. Hammer's personal letters to and from his wife, Lucy Hammer, family and friends are filed under the letter H. The second category is correspondence to and from company or corporate addresses involving mostly business matters such as product and process information, price and service quotes, complaints, work proposals, and consultation recommendations. It is also filed in alphabetical order by correspondent institutional name. The last category is internal company correspondence concerning the day-to-day management of MIF Co. Included in this category is the internal correspondence to and from Mr. Robert Thompson, who was Mr. Hammer's successor as president of the company. This correspondence is arranged in the order in which Mr. Hammer maintained it.
Series II: Reports and Surveys ( 1892-1970 ) contains reports, surveys, studies, and statistical information for the MIF Company. Among other documents, these records include annual reports, Boards of Directors meetings minutes, production studies, labor productivity studies, budgets, sales activities reports, and weekly operating and payroll analyses. These records are arranged in alphabetical order by title.
Series III: Personnel and Labor ( 1919-1962 ) contains records pertaining to executive employment and recruitment, labor contracts, labor policies, and employee records. Employee record cards and employee application records contain personal information on both management and non-management MIF Co. employees, such as: name, address, date of birth, physical attributes, pay rates, etc. N.B.: Individually identifiable information may not be recorded from employee records except for genealogical use in employee relations and policies may also be found in the interoffice memoranda in Series I: Correspondence and in Series II: Reports and Surveys.
Series IV: Subject Files ( undated, 1900-1970 ) contains reference material by MIF Co. concerning the processes and machinery used in the production of descriptions, machinery parts' listings, required standards and specification guides, and photographs of machinery. These records are arranged in alphabetical order by title.
Series V: Reference Materials ( 1892-1982 ) contains reference materials maintained by Mr. Hammer on companies and organizations other than MIF Co. These various materials include iron and steel industry directories and information, corporate histories, handbooks, and reports. These records are arranged in alphabetical order by topic. There are also industry catalogs and price lists which are arranged in alphabetical order by company name. MIF Co.'s catalogs and price lists are also contained in this group of records.
Series VI: Memorabilia, Biographical and Historical Records ( undated, 1854-1987 ) contains material concerning Thorvald F. Hammer's life and career, the history of MIF Co., and assorted memorabilia. These include such materials as newspaper clippings, photographs, published and unpublished articles, advertisements, and handwritten notes. Also included in this series are Mr. Hammer's models of various iron production processes, his consultant blueprints, and one box of iron product samples.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of records pertaining to Connecticut business and industry. See especially, Malleable Iron Fittings Company Records. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Organizations:
Malleable Iron Fittings Company.
Subjects:
Iron industry and trade—Connecticut—History—2oth century.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Personal Papers.; Publications.; Photographs.; Blueprints.; Administrative Records.; Financial Records.
Occupations:
Industrialist and Engineer
Restrictions on Access
Employee Record Cards and Employment Application Records are restricted to scholarly and genealogical use. In order to protect confidentiality, individually identifiable information may not be recorded except for genealogical use. Other than these records, there are no restrictions on the use of the collection.
Custodial History
The personal and business papers of Thorvald Frederick Hammer were donated to the University of Connecticut Foundation by his wife, Lucy T. Hammer, in March, 1988.
Acquisition Information
The Papers were transferred from the University of Connecticut Foundation to the Historical Manuscripts and Archives Department of the University of Connecticut Libraries (now Archives & Special Collections) in 1989.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Correspondence, 1931-1981
  - Subseries A: Personal and Individual Business Correspondence, 1931-1981
    - A — V, 1931-1981 (Box 1:, Folder 1-25)
    - W — Z, 1956-1980 (Box 2:, Folder 26-28)
  - Subseries B: Companies and Corporate Correspondence, 1957-1981
    - A — M, 1960-1980 (Box 2:, Folder 29-41)
    - O — Z, 1957-1981 (Box 3:, Folder 42-51)
  - Subseries C: Interoffice Memoranda, undated, 1940-1967
    - Personnel Office, 1950-1962 (Box 3:, Folder 52)
    - Annealing Department #1, 1948-1965 (Box 3:, Folder 53-54)
    - Yard Department #3, 1953-1960 (Box 3:, Folder 55)
    - Core Department #5, 1954-1966 (Box 3:, Folder 56)
    - Coupler Department #6, 1948-1960 (Box 3:, Folder 57)
    - Power Plant #7, 1948-1960 (Box 3:, Folder 58-59)
    - General Sales and Budgets, 1962 (Box 3:, Folder 60)
    - Production Control, 1960-1961 (Box 3:, Folder 61)
    - Warehouses, 1955-1962 (Box 3:, Folder 62)
    - Mall Foundry Department #8, 1940-1966 (Box 4:, Folder 63-72)
    - Purchasing Department, 1953-1964 (Box 4:, Folder 73)
    - Galvanizing Department #9, 1947-1967 (Box 4:, Folder 74)
    - Inspection Department #11, 1950-1961 (Box 4:, Folder 75)
    - Machine Shop #12, 1950-1958 (Box 4:, Folder 76)
    - Pattern Department #14, 1954-1959 (Box 4:, Folder 77)
    - Shipping Department #16-17, 1950-2964 (Box 4:, Folder 78-79)
    - Steel Foundry # 19, 1951-1966 (Box 4:, Folder 80-86)
    - Laboratory, 1950-1961 (Box 4:, Folder 87)
    - Final Inspection Department #24, 1954-1961 (Box 4:, Folder 88)
    - Quality Control, 1951-1963 (Box 4:, Folder 89-91)
    - Department #26 (Blank Fittings Dept.), 1951-1962 (Box 5:, Folder 92)
    - Emery Department #28, 1950-1962 (Box 5:, Folder 93)
    - Galvanizing Machine Department #29, 1956-1957 (Box 5:, Folder 94)
    - Fitting Sales Department, 1950-1964 (Box 5:, Folder 95-98)
    - Maintenance Department #33, 1950-1961 (Box 5:, Folder 99)
    - Unions #47, 1955-1966 (Box 5:, Folder 100)
    - Pole Line Hardware #58, 1955-1966 (Box 5:, Folder 101-102)
    - Unidentified, 1949-1961 (Box 5:, Folder 103)
    - Cafeteria, 1951-1957 (Box 5:, Folder 104)
    - Employment and First Aid, 1958-63 (Box 5:, Folder 105-106)
    - Watchmen, 1949-1958 (Box 5:, Folder 107)
    - Vacation Policies, 1950-1963 (Box 5:, Folder 108)
    - Wages, 1950-1959 (Box 5:, Folder 109)
    - Holidays, 1950-1962 (Box 5:, Folder 110)
    - Milestone Club, 1950-1963 (Box 5:, Folder 111)
    - Real estate, 1953-1963 (Box 5:, Folder 112)
    - Department Account Guides, undated (Box 5:, Folder 113)
- Series II: Reports and Surveys, 1892-1970
  - Agenda for Board of Directors' Meetings, 1962-1963 (Box 6:, Folder 114)
  - Ajax economic study, 1963 (Box 6:, Folder 115)
  - Analysis of core size standards, 1955 (Box 6:, Folder 116)
  - Annual stockholders' report, 1936-1960 (Box 6:, Folder 117-139)
  - Board of Directors and stockholders meetings' reports, 1939-1962 (Box 6:, Folder 140-141)
  - Committee on recapitalization, 1952-1953 (Box 6:, Folder 142)
  - Cooper Alloy Foundry Company, 1951 (Box 6:, Folder 143)
  - Core blower, 1964 (Box 6:, Folder 144)
  - Core shooter, 1963-1964 (Box 6:, Folder 145)
  - Core making, 1963 (Box 6:, Folder 146)
  - Dayton Malleable Iron Company, 1941-1942 (Box 6:, Folder 147)
  - Demmler Brothers, 1952-1955 (Box 6:, Folder 148)
  - Ductile iron study report, 1959-1962 (Box 6:, Folder 149)
  - European foundry visits, 1962-1963 (Box 6:, Folder 150)
  - Federal Foundry Supply Company, 1957-1960 (Box 6:, Folder 151)
  - Fitting sales records and reports, 1929-1951 (Box 6:, Folder 152-157)
  - Foundry production, 1955 (Box 7:, Folder 158)
  - Fragile castings, 1962-1964 (Box 7:, Folder 159)
  - Galvanizing machine study, 1955 (Box 7:, Folder 160)
  - Hoppers and bins, 1966 (Box 7:, Folder 161)
  - Hot box core machine, 1961-1963 (Box 7:, Folder 162)
  - International Molding Machine Company, 1938-1940 (Box 7:, Folder 163)
  - Jervis B. Webb Company, 1955 (Box 7:, Folder 164)
  - John Deere Malleable Works, 1955 (Box 7:, Folder 165)
  - Lab reports, 1892-1901 (Box 7:, Folder 166)
  - Labor payroll study, 1907 (Box 7:, Folder 167)
  - Labor production charts, 1923-1943 (Box 7:, Folder 168)
  - Machinery purchases, 1964 (Box 7:, Folder 169)
  - Mail foundry improvements, 1962-1963 (Box 7:, Folder 170)
  - Mall induction melting, 1963 (Box 7:, Folder 171)
  - Malleable melting, 1964 (Box 7:, Folder 172)
  - Malleable melting: air furnace, 1962-1964 (Box 7:, Folder 173)
  - Malm, Alex, 1943-1944 (Box 7:, Folder 174)
  - Market survey, 1924-1946 (Box 7:, Folder 175)
  - Milwaukee Foundry Company, 1941-1943 (Box 7:, Folder 176)
  - Mold blowing, 1951-1952 (Box 7:, Folder 177)
  - Molding automation, 1962-1963 (Box 7:, Folder 178)
  - Old plant visits, 1921-1956 (Box 7:, Folder 179)
  - Overseas visits, 1967 (Box 7:, Folder 180)
  - Overtime reports, 1957-1962 (Box 7:, Folder 181)
  - Pitcairn Company, 1941 (Box 7:, Folder 182)
  - Plans, forecasts and budgets, 1960 (Box 7:, Folder 183)
  - Pole Hardware Department, 1944-1956 (Box 7:, Folder 184)
  - Pole Hardware studies, 1928-1933 (Box 7:, Folder 185)
  - Quarterly stockholders' reports, 1957-1959 (Box 7:, Folder 186)
  - Reorganization study, 1957 (Box 7:, Folder 187)
  - Reports of new pattern equipment, 1956-1957 (Box 7:, Folder 188)
  - Reports on sand control process, 1957-1959 (Box 7:, Folder 189)
  - Sales activities reports, 1955 (Box 7:, Folder 190)
  - Sales and marketing annual report, 1958 (Box 7:, Folder 191)
  - Sales budgets, 1940-1960 (Box 7:, Folder 192)
  - Sales bulletins, 1957-1962 (Box 7:, Folder 193)
  - Sand cooling, 1961-1966 (Box 7:, Folder 194-196)
  - Steel foundry reports, 1956-1960 (Box 8:, Folder 197)
  - Steel plan reports, 1939-1958 (Box 8:, Folder 198)
  - Studies on capitalization, 1936-1945 (Box 8:, Folder 199)
  - Study of malleable castings jobbing vs. pole hardware, 1945 (Box 8:, Folder 200)
  - Study of profitability of pole hardware, 1945 (Box 8:, Folder 201)
  - Survey of market organization, 1954 (Box 8:, Folder 202)
  - Thomas Devlin Company, 1942 (Box 8:, Folder 203)
  - Visits to competitive manufacturers, 1954-1963 (Box 8:, Folder 204-205)
  - Visits to MIF customers, 1953-1955 (Box 8:, Folder 206)
  - Weekly operating reports, 1960-1961 (Box 8:, Folder 207)
  - Weekly operating analyses, 1954-1960 (Box 8:, Folder 208)
- Series III: Personnel and Labor, 1919-1962
  - Ahl, Henry C.: employment of, 1958-1959 (Box 9:, Folder 209)
  - Baxter, Jim salary and Tom Beardsley's employment, 1957-1962 (Box 9:, Folder 210)
  - Employee's handbook, 1962 (Box 9:, Folder 211)
  - Subseries A: Employee Record Cards, 1919-1963
    - A — J, 1960-1963
    - K — Z, 1960-1963
    - Labor contracts, 1937-1962 (Box 9:, Folder 212-222)
    - Payroll sheets, 1919 (Box 9:, Folder 223)
    - Process engineer applications, 1956-1957 (Box 9:, Folder 224)
    - Robinson, Bob: employment of, 1958-1960 (Box 9:, Folder 225)
    - Salaries and commissions, 1958-1960 (Box 9:, Folder 226)
- Series IV: Subject Files, undated, 1900-1970
  - Acid and flux tank: library of parts, 1950-1955 (Box 9:, Folder 227)
  - Active file: cost funding, 1953-1966 (Box 9:, Folder 228)
  - Advanced steel, 1980 (Box 9:, Folder 229)
  - Automatic galvanizing machine, 1950-1962 (Box 9:, Folder 230)
  - Barrett Centrifugal Company, 1957-1981 (Box 9:, Folder 231-232)
  - Basket hook: library of parts, 1968 (Box 9:, Folder 233)
  - Bond metal finishers: Canada, 1976 (Box 9:, Folder 234)
  - Bruce Calder: engineer, 1979 (Box 9:, Folder 235)
  - Central control panel: library of parts, 1969 (Box 9:, Folder 236)
  - Centrifuge: library of parts, 1968 (Box 9:, Folder 237)
  - Centrifuge patent, 1961-1968 (Box 9:, Folder 238)
  - Completed information on automatic galvanizing kettles, 1953-1966 (Box 9:, Folder 239)
  - Cost estimate of old type carrier, 1952-1966 (Box 9:, Folder 240)
  - Cost of new style carrier, 1967-1969 (Box 9:, Folder 241)
  - Discharge reel: library of parts, undated (Box 9:, Folder 242)
  - Dross part and zinc pump, 1955-1956 (Box 9:, Folder 243)
  - Dross scoop: library of parts, 1960-1973 (Box 9:, Folder 244)
  - Dwight Foote Company, 1971-1976 (Box 9:, Folder 245)
  - Embrittlement specifications, 1949 (Box 9:, Folder 246)
  - Fitting packs, 1945-1966 (Box 9:, Folder 247)
  - Flux dam skimmer, 1950-1951 (Box 9:, Folder 248)
  - Fundicao Tupy S.A. (Brazil), 1973-1976 (Box 9:, Folder 249)
  - Galvalume, 1973-1977 (Box 9:, Folder 250)
  - “Galvamatic” trademark registration, 1967-1969 (Box 9:, Folder 251)
  - Galvanizing baskets: library of parts, 1969 (Box 9:, Folder 252)
  - Galvanizing machine patents, 1967-1969 (Box 9:, Folder 253)
  - Harrison Electronics Company, 1975 (Box 9:, Folder 254)
  - IVACO (TexasGulf Company), 1981 (Box 9:, Folder 255)
  - Jenne, Ken: old file, 1947-1950 (Box 10:, Folder 256)
  - Joslyn Company, 1971-1974 (Box 10:, Folder 257)
  - Kettle size formula, 1967-1969 (Box 10:, Folder 258)
  - Kettles, 1958-1959 (Box 10:, Folder 259)
  - Lancy Library, 1971-1975 (Box 10:, Folder 260)
  - MIF power and free converter, 1969 (Box 10:, Folder 261)
  - Minnesota Mining and Manufacturing (3M), 1963-1966 (Box 10:, Folder 262)
  - Monel pickle barrels, 1973-1975 (Box 10:, Folder 263)
  - Monel pickle tray: library of parts, 1968 (Box 10:, Folder 264)
  - New England Rack Company, 1972-1975 (Box 10:, Folder 265)
  - New type galvanizing machine, 1972-1975 (Box 10:, Folder 266)
  - Number 1 machine production chart, 1957 (Box 10:, Folder 267)
  - Olsen Industries, 1964-1978 (Box 10:, Folder 268)
  - Original patents, 1900-1970 (Box 10:, Folder 269-270)
  - Orville Jones, 1980-1981 (Box 10:, Folder 271)
  - Photographs
    - Automatic galvanizing machine, undated (Box 10:, Folder 272)
    - Automatic galvanizing rod and quench machine, 1964-1968 (Box 10:, Folder 273)
    - Basket type machine, 1959 (Box 10:, Folder 274)
    - Unidentified machine, ca. 1967-1968 (Box 10:, Folder 275)
    - Rack type machines, ca. 1967-1968 (Box 10:, Folder 276)
  - Pickle acids: fluxing, 1957-1966 (Box 10:, Folder 277)
  - Pickling acids, 1956 (Box 10:, Folder 278)
  - Pickling data, 1956 (Box 10:, Folder 279)
  - Pimples, 1959 (Box 10:, Folder 280)
  - Pipe galvanizing, 1966-1967 (Box 10:, Folder 281)
  - Pipe galvanizing: inquiries, 1960-1961 (Box 10:, Folder 282)
  - Preparation for galvanizing, 1967 (Box 10:, Folder 283)
  - Quench conversation: library of parts, 1966-1971 (Box 10:, Folder 284)
  - Quench tank and vibrators: library of parts, 1966-1971 (Box 10:, Folder 285)
  - Questionnaire forms, undated (Box 10:, Folder 286)
  - Rack link pins, 1968 (Box 10:, Folder 287)
  - Rotary flux machines: library of parts, 1967 (Box 10:, Folder 288)
  - Rotary pickle and flux machine: library of parts, 1967 (Box 10:, Folder 289)
  - Rotary quench and dry: library of parts, 1968 (Box 10:, Folder 290)
  - Salamoniac dispenser: library of parts, 1958 (Box 10:, Folder 291)
  - Senco Products Incorporated, 1980 (Box 10:, Folder 292)
  - Skimmer: Library of parts, 1956-1980 (Box 10:, Folder 293)
  - South Bay Barrel Painting Company, 1980 (Box 10:, Folder 294)
  - Spin-a-Batch system, 1973-1974 (Box 10:, Folder 295)
  - Star rod machine, 1967 (Box 10:, Folder 296)
  - Stockman Company, 1974-1975 (Box 10:, Folder 297)
  - Sutro, Ogden, 1964-1976 (Box 10:, Folder 298)
  - TexasGulf, Incorporated, 1978-1982 (Box 10:, Folder 299)
  - Transfer fork: library of parts, 1969 (Box 10:, Folder 300)
  - Tumbling process of nail galvanizing, 1980 (Box 10:, Folder 301)
  - Types of conveyors, 1969-1970 (Box 10:, Folder 302)
  - Typical layouts, 1966-1968 (Box 10:, Folder 303)
  - Wheeling Bronze, 1975 (Box 10:, Folder 304)
  - Wrong type of steel, 1950-1975 (Box 10:, Folder 305)
  - Zinc ash, 1959 (Box 10:, Folder 306)
  - Zinc drip eliminator: library of parts, 1960-1968 (Box 10:, Folder 307)
- Series V: Reference Materials, 1892-1982
  - American Hot Dip Galvanizing Association (AHDGA) Newsletters, 1966-1982 (Box 11:, Folder 308-309)
  - AHDGA reports, 1954-1974 (Box 11:, Folder 310-322)
  - Corporate and Industry Histories (Box 11:, Folder 323-326)
    - The American Malleable Cast Iron Industry by H.A. Schwartz, 1922
    - Arthur C. Walworth by James J. Walworth, 1922
    - “The Atlantic Wire Company” by Atlantic Wire Company, 1956
    - A Century of Dependability by Wilcox, Crittenden, and Company, 1947
    - “Changing Times” by the Albion Malleable Iron Company, 1950
    - A History of Steel Casting ed. By Arthur D. Graeff, 1949
    - Metal Fabrication by Risdon Manufacturing Company, ca. 1950
    - “One Hundred Years of Leadership” by Stanley B. Flagg Company, 1954
    - “Three Is a Company” by the Union Malleable Manufacturing Company, ca. 1950
    - United Engineering and Foundry Company by G.G. Beard, 1961
    - Yankee Toolmaker by the Bullard Company, 1955
  - Cost accounting system for malleable iron industry, 1934 (Box 11:, Folder 327)
  - Directory of Steel Foundries in the U.S. and Canada, 1967-1968 (Box 11:, Folder 328)
  - Directory of the Iron and Steel Works of the U.S., 1892 (Box 11:, Folder 329)
  - Hot Dip Galvanizing Association of England, 1964-1968 (Box 11:, Folder 330)
  - Malleable Founders Society: directory, 1936-1969 (Box 11:, Folder 331)
  - Manufacturers Obligations Under Connecticut Law, 1963, 1965 (Box 11:, Folder 332)
  - Pipe Fittings Manufacturers Association (PFMA) Reports, 1956-1965 (Box 12:, Folder 333-334)
  - PFMA constitution, 1956, 1962 (Box 12:, Folder 335)
  - PFMA directory, 1958-1966 (Box 12:, Folder 336)
  - PFMA military specifications, 1952 (Box 12:, Folder 337)
  - PFMA statistical reports, 1939 (Box 12:, Folder 338)
  - Production and Industry Handbooks (Box 12:, Folder 339-340)
    - The Commercial Market for Pearlitic Malleable Cast Iron by Donald L. Boyes, 1941
    - “Carbon and Low Alloy Steel Castings” by Steel Founders Society of America (SFSA), 1952
    - “Drafting Practices” by SFSA, c. 1965
    - “Elcometer dry Film Thickness Gage” by Gardner Laboratory, 1966
    - Galvanizing Manual and Directory by Galvanizers Association of Australia, c. 1965
    - Hot Dip Galvanizing by Anglo-American Council on Productivity, 1951
    - Job Evaluation and Merit Procedures for Steel Foundries by SFSA, undated
    - Malleable Sand and Core Practice Symposia by American Foundrymen's Association (AFA), 1946
    - Malleable Iron by AFA, 1940
    - NJZ Hot Dip Galvanizing Manual by New Jersey Zinc Company, 1972 (Box 12)
    - The National Plumbing Code by Vincent Manas, 1952
    - Properties of Some Metals and Alloys by the International Nickel Company, 1953
    - “Some Mechanical Properties of Cast Steels” by SFSA, ca. 1945
    - “Zinc Coatings” by Zinc Development Association, 1960
    - The Zinc Industry by the American Zinc Institute, 1949